2018年2月6日，重型猎鹰火箭从肯尼迪航天中心LC-39A发射台起飞
On the 6th of February 2018, the Falcon Heavy lifted off from pad 39A at the Kennedy Space Center
它是最近一段时间最令人期待的火箭发射之一
It was one of the most highly anticipated rocket launches in recent history,
告诉了世界最新一代可复用火箭已经来临
showing that a new era of reusable rockets had arrived
任务非常成功，火箭上的汽车和小人也吸引了全世界的目光
The mission was successful and images of Starman in his Roadster caught the world's attention
那为什么重型猎鹰迟迟没有再次上天？
So why has it taken so long for the Falcon Heavy to fly again?
本期视频我们将了解为何重型猎鹰首飞拖了那么久
In this video we’re going to look at why it took so long for the Falcon Heavy to fly in the first place
我们还将了解为何它没有那么多的发射任务
We’re also going to look at why it doesn’t have many missions lined up
以及这款火箭未来将会怎样
and what the future holds for the rocket
在2011年，太空叉首次公布重型猎鹰计划
In 2011, SpaceX unveiled their plans for the Falcon Heavy
并且宣布首飞时间暂定2013年
and announced that the first test flight was expected to take place in 2013
然而，把三个猎鹰九号火箭捆一起远比想象的困难得多
However, strapping three Falcon 9’s together started to prove more difficult than expected
加上2015年和2016年的一年一炸
and with two failures in 2015 and 2016
太空叉不得不把工作重心转移到提高猎鹰九号火箭可靠性上去
SpaceX had to shift their attention to improving the reliability of the Falcon 9
这很大程度上影响了重型猎鹰火箭的研发
This caused major delays in the development of the Falcon Heavy
加之，太空叉还打算验证重型猎人载人的可行性
On top of that, SpaceX were also planning to verify the Falcon Heavy for crewed flights
然而事实证明花费的时间比预期的要长得多
However it became increasingly clear that this would take much longer than expected
同时越来越多的时间和资金被用于研发BFR(StarShip)
and with more time and money going into Starship's development
他们决定把重猎载人的计划取消
they decided to cancel the idea of flying humans on the Falcon Heavy
在修复了猎鹰九号的问题之后，火箭在2017年的发射全部成功
After fixing the issues that plagued the Falcon 9, SpaceX had a flawless year in 2017
于是在2018年初，重型猎鹰火箭被推出总装厂，准备其首次飞行
and at the start of 2018, the Falcon Heavy was rolled out of its hangar, ready for its first test flight
数千人齐聚卡角，全球上百万人在网络上观看
Thousands of people gathered around the Cape and millions of people around the world watched online
重型猎鹰直刺苍穹的画面
as the Falcon Heavy soared into the sky
在成功演示了重型猎鹰拥有运送载荷的能力之后
After demonstrating that the Falcon Heavy could fly and deliver payloads successfully
重型猎鹰看起来已经可以开始为首批商业客户运送卫星了
it looked like it was ready to start launching satellites for its first customers
包括通信卫星Arabsat和美国军方
This included the Arabsat communications satellite as well as the US military
后者在2012年就已经打算用重型猎鹰发射他们的卫星了
who had arranged to launch their satellites on the Falcon Heavy way back in 2012
这些发射原定在首飞后几个月进行
These launches were originally scheduled just a few months after the initial test flight
但太空叉的精力却转移到了升级后的猎鹰九号Block5上
but with an effort being made to launch the upgraded Block 5 Falcon 9
导致重猎遥二再次被咕咕咕
SpaceX once again fell behind with the Falcon Heavy
尽管目前看来重型猎鹰可能没有我们预期那么多的飞行次数
Although the Falcon Heavy might not have flown as many times as we would have liked by now
别忘了太空叉这些年已经带给我们多少令人震撼的发射了
it’s important to point out that SpaceX have spoiled us with an unprecedented number of launches over the last few years
光是2018年，太空叉就使用猎鹰九号完成20次成功的发射
In 2018 alone, SpaceX achieved 20 successful launches of the Falcon 9
而别人家的火箭，比如Ariane、Atlas、Delta各自也就发射了3到6次
whilst other rockets like the Ariane, Atlas and Delta only managed between 3 and 6 launches
而重型猎鹰没有这么多发射任务的主要原因之一
One of the main reasons that the Falcon Heavy doesn’t have many missions lined up
是卫星方面的供需关系
is down to the supply and demand of satellites
重型猎鹰是重型运载火箭，能够把重达23吨的卫星送进近地轨道
根据最新版猎鹰火箭用户手册，
猎鹰九号(重型猎鹰和猎鹰九号二级相同)的载荷支架
最高只能承载11吨重的载荷，因此23吨仅为理论值
The Falcon Heavy is a heavy lift vehicle, capable of carrying satellites of up to 23 tonnes into lower Earth orbit
更重要的是，它还可以做到回收
Most importantly, it’s able to do this whilst being reusable
使其成为火箭市场最便宜的重型运载火箭
making it the most affordable heavy lift rocket on the market
虽然这个运力很强大，但绝大多数卫星重量都在2到8吨之间
While this is an impressive amount of capability, the majority of satellites typically have a mass between 2 and 8 tonnes
更加适合用猎鹰九号这种小一点的火箭发射
making smaller rockets like the Falcon 9 far more suitable
小卫星市场的崛起也让像Rocketlab的电子号火箭站了起来
The rise in the small satellite market has allowed private company Rocketlab to thrive with their Electron rocket
这种小火箭发射一次只要不超过五百万美元
This small rocket is able to launch payloads for less than $5 million
也因为对这种火箭需求的高涨，电子号在2019年发射日程排得满满的
and due to the demand for rockets like this, it has a busy schedule lined up for 2019
虽然重型猎鹰的任务屈指可数
Although there are only a handful of missions currently lined up for the Falcon Heavy
它的未来还是很令人兴奋的
its future is still very exciting
今年，太空叉将用重型猎鹰火箭发射通信卫星Arabsat
This year, SpaceX will launch the Falcon Heavy carrying the Arabsat communication satellite
更令人兴奋的是，太空叉将回收全部三枚一级火箭
What makes this even more exciting is that SpaceX plan to land all three boosters
并用它们在8周后进行下一次重型猎鹰的任务
and reuse them for the next Falcon Heavy mission just 8 weeks later
任务将携带美国军方的25个实验卫星
This mission will be carrying 25 experimental satellites for the US Military
如果一切顺利，将打破太空叉之前10周翻新火箭的纪录
and if all goes well, this would break SpaceX’s previous turnaround record of 10 weeks
所以虽然重猎遥二让我们等了很久
So although it has taken a while for the Falcon Heavy to fly again
我们却能领会到建造人类有史以来最有代表性的火箭所需的大量工程
we can appreciate the enormous amount of engineering that has gone into making one of the most iconic rockets ever made
字幕翻译给虫，欢迎点赞投币收藏分享转发评论关注充电~
感谢Primal Space的帮助每个视频撰写文稿查找资料的赞助者
Thank you to the Primal Space patrons who helped to write and research each video
如果你想赞助Primal Space频道并加入我们专有Discord群
If you'd like to contribute Primal Space and join our exclusive Discord
请访问patreon.com/primalspace
please visit patreon.com/primalspace
满100名赞助者后会抽三位赠送坎巴拉太空计划
where we will be giving away 3 copies of Kerbal Space Program once we reach 100 patrons
所以记得关注，方便我们讨论、学习所有和太空有关的知识
So make sure you've subscribed, so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space
非常感谢您的观看，我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching, and I'll see you in the next video